João Victor Simonassi

+55 21 96675-5666 jsimonassi@id.uff.br linkedin.com/in/jsimonassi/ joaovictorsimonassi.com.br/

Mobile developer with over 4 years of experience. I develop scalable and easy-to-maintain solutions using React Native and native technologies. I have experience in creating native packages and I love working on applications that are in direct contact with the end user. Seeing my solutions contributing and impacting people's lives is extremely rewarding.

EXPERIENCE

Radix Engineering and Software — Software Engineer III

JULY DE 2020 - PRESENT

Allocated in the Technos project (One of the largest watch companies in Brazil), I develop mobile and web solutions with the aim of retrieving information and configuring settings on the company's smartwatches. Throughout this period, I was able to contribute to several activities and improvements, such as:

- Leadership of the team in the creation and development of two mobile applications that currently make up significantly the Technos group's revenue;
- Launch of more than 10 watches in various company applications;
- Refactoring of the exercise flow in the app, migrating to a native architecture with Java and Objective-C (through the creation of a native package for react native). Using this architecture guaranteed better performance for the end user and better usability in the application;
- Creation of several libraries for the project. I highlight here the library of visual components that reduced the development time of new projects based on code reuse.
- Creation of pipelines in bitrise that automate the flow of generating test builds and sending applications to stores in apps with more than 100 thousand active users monthly.

Tools and technologies: Java, Kotlin, Objective C, Typescript, React Native, ReactJS, Jest, React Testing Library, Firebase, Styled Components, MVVM, Foreground Services, Fused Location Provider, Room Database, Bitrise, C# + .net, Ruby on Rails, and others.

La Salle Abel School — Mobile Development Internship

SEPTEMBER 2019 - JULY 2020

I developed native mobile applications (Kotlin and Java) that helped the educational projects proposed by teachers. Throughout this period, I was able to contribute to various activities, such as:

- Development of mathematics games used in internal competitions between classes at the institution;
- Development of an application that consumed the Cloud Vision API transforming images (screenshot of the user's handwriting) into text and later into voice. Students with literacy difficulties used this tool to improve their writing and check for points of failure;

Tools and technologies: Java, Kotlin, Firebase, Retrofit, entre outras.

EDUCATION

Federal Fluminense University, Computer Science—Bachelor's Degree

JULY DE 2017 - JULY DE 2023

Graduated in Computer Science from Universidade Federal Fluminense - UFF.

EXTRA COURSES

Android Architecture Components: ViewModel, LiveData e Room, Alura 30 hours

DECEMBER 2021 - JANUARY 2021

Development of Android applications with Kotlin using practices recommended by Google.

React Native - Design System e Context Api, Alura 30 hours

IULY 2021 - AUGUST 2021

Implementation of projects using Context Api, ensuring a scalable and performant architecture.

Android Development, Udemy - 40 hours

JULY 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Development of native mobile applications using Android Studio. Manipulation of layouts, media, storage, as well as other requirements for creating applications.

PROJECTS

The main projects can be found in my portfolio: https://joaovictorsimonassi.com.br/

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Working on open source projects

Whenever it makes sense, I work on open source projects. My last contribution was to the react native permissions library, ensuring support for new versions of android. Release link: https://github.com/zoontek/react-native-permissions/releases/tag/3.1.0

LANGUAGES

English - B2

Inglês - CNA

JANUARY 2017 - DECEMBER 2017

Lucas Maffei (Particular)

AUGUST 2023 - PRESENT